# 这一曲舞你应该会跳 #
Here's a dance you should know
# 当灯光黯淡 #
When the lights are down low
# 带上你的舞伴 起舞吧 #
Grab your baby, then go
根 据 真 实 事 件 改 编
# 带上你的舞伴 起舞吧 #
Grab your baby, then go
根 据 真 实 事 件 改 编
# 尽情摇摆吧 #
Do the hucklebuck
马萨诸塞州 韦尔弗利特
# 尽情摇摆吧 #
Do the hucklebuck
马萨诸塞州 韦尔弗利特
# 尽情摇摆吧 #
Do the hucklebuck
马萨诸塞州 韦尔弗利特
1951 年 11月
# 尽情摇摆吧 #
Do the hucklebuck
马萨诸塞州 韦尔弗利特
# 如果你不知道如何去做 #
If you don't know how to do it
马萨诸塞州 韦尔弗利特
1951 年 11月
# 孩子 你还真是倒霉 #
Boy, you're out of luck
马萨诸塞州 韦尔弗利特
1951 年 11月
# 孩子 你还真是倒霉 #
Boy, you're out of luck
# 推开你的舞伴 #
Push your partner out
# 然后身体站直 #
Then you hunch your back
# 然后动动你的髋部 #
Start a little movement in your sacroilliac
# 像蛇一样摇摆 像鸭一样摇摆 #
Wiggle like a snake, waddle like a duck
Bernie 说真的
Now, Bernie, seriously,
这就是约好见面的地方吗
this is where they asked us to meet?
没错 你想说什么
Yeah, what do you mean?
我想我看见她了
Oh, I think I see her.
- 在哪儿 - 那一定是她
- Where? - Oh, that's gotta be her.
那我们接下来做什么呢
All right, so, what are we gonna do?
来这里喝杯奶昔吗 Bernie
Are we gonna grab a milkshake, Bernie?
就为这来的吗
Is that why we're here?
没错 我想是的
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, I guess.
那你可要欠我一个大人情了
All right, you're gonna owe me big for this.
那么...
So...
你觉得我该换件衬衣吗
You think I shoulda worn the other shirt?
你现在这样挺好
You look nice.
我不知道 Gus 也许...
I don't know, Gus, maybe she...
要是她不喜欢
what if she don't like
我的外表呢
the look of me or something?
Bernie 得了吧 你真的
Bernie, come on, are you sure...
这样想吗 那她呢
Are you serious? What about her?
你不也很想
Aren't you dying to see
见到她的样子吗
what she looks like?
她说不定特难看
She could be a dog.
不 她不是
No, she isn't a dog.
说不定呢
She could be.
我脑海里
I already know
已经知道她长什么样了
what she looks like in my head.
她不难看
she isn't a dog.
这么说...
So, uh...
你和她电话聊天
You've been talking to her
已经好几周了 对吗
for weeks on the phone, right?
- 是的 - 对吧
- Yeah. - Right?
没错
Yeah.
只和你聊天 她就喜欢上你了 Bernie
She likes you, from talkin' to you, Bernie.
我觉得你完全不用担心
And I don't think you gotta worry about
她会看不上你
her getting a good look at ya.
对你来说这根本不是问题
That ain't never been your problem.
我们走吧
Let's go.
快来
Come on.
真该换件衣服的
Shoulda worn the other shirt.
我的风险更大
I'm the one takin' the risk.
和我约会的女孩
Doublin' with some girl
我连话都没说过
I never even spoke to,
更别说见面了
let alone seen.
不知为何这个叫Miriam的女孩
I don't know why this Miriam girl
非得要求今晚来个四人约会
says it's gotta be a double date anyway.
也许她对我的态度还不是很确定
Maybe she's not sure about me yet.
怎么可能有姑娘
How can anybody
对你不确定呢 Bernie
not be sure about you, Bernie?
谢谢你 Gus
Yeah, thanks, Gus.
嘿 可别把这件事
Yeah, hey, don't tell the other guys
告诉队里的人
down at the station about this.
你又不是以前没约会过
It's not like you've never been on a date before.
都好了吗
All set there?
请问 你是Miriam吗
Excuse me, are you Miriam?
不是 我是她朋友
No, I'm her friend.
她在...
She's, uh...
- 你好 我是Gus - 我是Catherine
- Hi, how ya doin', I'm Gus? - Catherine.
我们一会儿再聊
We'll talk later.
再见
Bye.
你好
Hi.
等等
Wait.
你是Bernie Webber吧
You are Bernie Webber, right?
是的 我是Bernie
Yeah, yeah, I'm Bernie.
你们俩 一起来喝一杯吧
Hey, you two, let's go grab drink.
- 你想来吗 - 好
- You wanna go? - Sure.
你好
How you doin'?
- 我是Gus - 知道吗...
- I'm Gus. - You know...
刚才有那么一瞬间 我以为
For a minute there I thought it was
电话亭里站着的是一头斯摩基熊
Smokey the Bear makin' a call in that booth.
斯摩基熊 是美国森林防火公益传播的卡通代言形象
因为你的大衣
'Cause of your jacket.
Bernie Miriam从没坐过船
Bernie... Miriam's never been on a boat.
她怕水
She's scared of the water.
从没坐过吗
Has she never?
我说过 我不明白
I told her I don't know how
她怎么要和一名海岸警卫队员约会
she's gonna date a guy in the Coast Guard.
我不怕水 我就住在海角那里
I'm not scared, I live on the Cape.
别担心 Miriam
Don't worry, Miriam, you know,
我们... 我们出海时也会害怕
we... we all get scared out there.
我不怕水 Bernie
I'm not afraid of the water, Bernie.
只是在夜里才会害怕
It scares me at night, that's all, you know.
因为看不见水下有什么
You can't see what's underneath.
只是更多的水而已
Just more water.
知道吗 随着夜幕降临我会变得更风趣
You know, I... I get funnier as the night goes on.
那个 为什么... 你为什么不想
So, well, why... why didn't you want
和我约会 为什...
to meet me for a date? Wha...
为什么要等这么久
Why did you wait so long?
我不知道你是否...
I didn't know if you'd be a...
是否什么
If... if I what?
- 你知道的 - 我不知道
- You know. - No.
你太帅了
You are so handsome,
我不知道
I just didn't know
你会不会看上我
if you'd be attracted to me.
哦 别 Miriam
Oh, God, no, Miriam
你和我想象的一模一样
you're exactly how I pictured you.
- 是吗 - 是的
- Yeah? - Oh, yeah.
而且更美
Better.
知道吗 我哥哥
You know what, my... my brother
他总说
he always says
感觉对了 一定错不了
when you know, you just know.
哪个
Which one?
我想是指所有事吧
All of it, I guess everything.
不 我是说哪个哥哥
No, I mean, which brother.
Paul 我哥哥Paul
Paul, my brother Paul.
是那个在德国打过仗的哥哥吗
He's the one who fought over in Germany?
没错 在德国
In Germany, yeah.
他是老大 也是父亲最喜欢的
He's the oldest, father's favorite.
我的三个哥哥
All three of my brothers
都打过仗
went over to the war.
他是你父亲的什么
He's your father's what?
我们今晚得让Miriam上船
We should get Miriam out on a boat tonight,
你觉得怎样 Bernie
what did you say, Bernie?
我们坐平底船出海 一定好玩
We take out the dory, gonna be fantastic.
这样不行 Gus
You know we can't do that, Gus,
会惹麻烦的
we can get in trouble.
拜托 Bernie 会很有趣的
Come on, Bernie, it'll be fun.
规矩就是规矩
Rules are rules.
不 我们... 我们不用划太远
No, we... we... we don't gotta row out far.
只是让这位美女
Just as so this sweet girl
再也不必说自己从没坐过船了
can say she's been on a boat, that's it.
划小船吗 不行
A row boat? No!
不 不 不 小船太...
No, no, no, small boats are...
换条大点的船怎么样
How about one of those bigger boats...
系在码头上的那种
tied up to the dock.
如果Bernie陪我 我就去
If Bernie's with me, I'll do it.
渔船吗
Oh, a fishing boat?
除了要我们帮忙靠船 那些渔民
Those fishermen don't want us around,
都不愿让我们靠近渔船
unless we're pulling them in.
他们认为那片水域只属于他们
They think they own the God damned water.
他们可不怎么友好
They're not very nice.
拜托 别犯傻了 Miriam
Come on, don't be such a fathead, Miriam.
没错
Yeah.
我们一起坐船出去
Let's go out on the dory,
有什么好怕的
what's there to be afraid of?
谁知道水下有什么 是吗
What's underneath, right?
Stello先生 你好吗
Hey, Mr. Stello, how's it goin'?
- 你好 Bernie - Ryder先生
- Hey, Bernie. - Mr. Ryder.
你看见那位...
Hey, so you see that...
坐在那儿的姑娘了吗
see that girl sitting over there?
穿着大衣
The one with the coat
看起来像只熊的那位吗 Bernie
looks like a bear, Bernie?
- 没错 - 她很显眼
- Yeah. - Can't miss her.
我也这么说
I said the same thing myself,
真好笑 你竟然和我说的一样
funny you should say that, yeah.
看上去就像斯摩基 对吧 斯摩基熊
Looks like Smokey, right? Smokey the Bear?
我不知道什么是斯摩基熊 Bernie
I don't know no Smokey, Bernie.
它... 是个卡通人物
It's... it's just a cartoon.
对了 Stello先生
Anyway, Mr. Stello,
她... 她觉得
she... she thinks
自己害怕搭船出海
she's scared of going out on a boat.
我觉得
And I don't think
我们不该划平底船出去
we should row out on a dory,
我不愿让她
I don't want to
吐在那件漂亮的大衣上
get her sick on that nice big coat.
所以能否...
So I was wondering if...
所以 你想带她
So, you wanna take her
坐着Anna G号在港口转转 是吗
on the Anna G around the harbor?
没错
Yeah.
有心出海
Can't row out on that dory,
却不敢划小船 对吗 Bernie
even if you wanted, right, Bernie?
Carl 别说了
Carl, stop.
一周年就要到了
Year anniversary's coming,
我姐姐现在还住在我家
My sister's now livin' in my house.
你对此作何感想 Bernie
How's it going with you, Bernie?
够了 Carl 他当时尽力了
That's enough, Carl, he did all he could.
我很抱歉 Nickerson先生
I am sorry, Mr. Nickerson.
我无意惹你伤心
I didn't mean to upset you,
只想找Stello先生
just wanted to ask Mr. Stello about
借一条船
borrowin' a boat.
安妮·G
我扶你
Got you! I got you!
安妮·G
把手给我
Give me your hands.
没事的
It's okay.
1952年 2月 17日
# 庄园漆黑一片 #
Now the hacienda's dark.
# 小镇陷入沉睡 #
The town is sleeping.
# 离别时刻已到 #
Now the time has come to part.
# 潸然泪下 #
The time for weeping.
# 愿主与你同在 我的至爱 #
Vaya con dios, my darling.
跟着我的手势 好吗
Just follow my arms, okay?
跟着我
Stay with me.
关键是... 找准节拍
It's all about... it's all about the rhythm.
懂了吗 那... 我们试试吧
Okay? So, it's... so, it's, here we go.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
右 左 右
Right, left, right.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
一 二 三 一
One, two, three. One...
我没法和着拍子数一二三
I can't one, two, three to this.
我们还是去坐着吧 Bernie
Let's just sit down, Bernie?
不 宝贝
No, Sweetheart,
你只需要
Look, all you gotta do is...
放轻松
you gotta relax
耐心跟着我的动作
and be patient and settle in my hand.
你看 像这样
Hey, look, just, here
跟着我 有感觉吗
settle in my hand, you feel that?
只需听着音乐
Just, listen to the music.
来 一 二 三
And... One, two, three.
一 二 三 右 左 右
One, two, three. Right, left, right.
右 左 右
Right, left, right.
非常好
You're doing great.
# 拂晓即将来临 #
Now the dawn is breaking through.
# 迎来灰暗明天 #
A gray tomorrow.
# 但我们的回忆 不断浮现 #
But the memories we share are there to borrow.
# 愿主与你同在 我的至爱 #
Vaya con dios, my darling.
你会娶我吗
Will you marry me?
什么
What?
你会娶我吗
Will you marry me?
不
No.
# 愿主与你同在 我的至爱 #
Vaya con dios, my darling.
# 愿主与你同在 #
Vaya con dios...
Miriam 等等
Miriam, hold on.
外面太冷了 宝贝
It's cold, Sweetheart,
回里面去吧
Don't you wanna go back inside?
演奏还没结束呢
The... The band's not through.
你不冷吗
It's cold. Do you feel that?
暴风雪要来了
There's a storm coming.
好吧
Okay.
好什么
Okay, what?
我们结婚吧
Okay, let's get married.
我只是... 只是不想
I just... I don't wanna...
不想什么
Wanna what?
我们才交往几个月
Well, it's only been a few months
而且现在还是冬天
and it's still winter after all,
而且... 而且...
and... and... look, you know
暴风雪要来了
there... there's a storm comin'
就像去年那场一样
it's just like this one come through last year.
这和...
What does that...
我听说风暴不会从这里过境
I heard it's gonna miss us.
不一定的 谁知道呢
Yeah, but maybe not, you never know.
很难说的
You never know.
有些人...
There's some people just...
他们就不适应... 这个
they're just not cut out for... for this.
有时一去就再也回不来了
Sometimes you go out and you don't come back.
你是在说暴风雪 还是婚姻 Bernie
Are you talkin' about the storm, or marriage, Bernie?
我说的是暴风雪 不是吗
I think I'm talking about the storm, right?
你怕暴风雪吗
You're scared of a storm?
不
No.
我不想让任何人失望
I don't wanna disappoint nobody.
而且...
And...
我也不想失去你 因为我爱你
I don't wanna lost you, I love you.
所以...
So...
好 我们结婚吧
yeah, let's get married.
真的吗
You sure?
真的
Oh, yeah.
什么时候
When?
你要我来选日子吗
You want me to pick a date?
不 这要看你想什么时候结婚
No, when... when do you wanna get married.
- 四月十六日 - 好
- April 16th. - Okay.
好 那就四月十六日
Okay, April 16th it is.
但... 但我...
But... but I... but I...
我得先征得Cluff的同意
I gotta ask permission from Cluff first.
你得征得同意吗
Ya gotta ask permission?
是的 指挥官得同意才行
Yeah, it's... it's from my commanding officer,
这是海岸警卫队的规定
it's Coast Guard regulation.
不过我保证 明天就去问他
But, promise, I'll ask him tomorrow.
好的 Bernie
Okay, Bernie.
我送你回家吧
Let's get you home.
这样你就能跳舞了
Then you can dance.
看 已经开始下雪了
Ah, look at that. It's already starting to snow. Hmm?
彭德尔顿 - T2油轮
马萨诸塞州 查塔姆 东北处 10 英里
你能听到我的声音吗 船长
Can you hear me over this hummin', Captain?
他们上个月焊接的那条裂缝
That fracture they welded
可承受不了这样的大浪 船长
last month is not gonna hold in these seas, Captain,
如果颠簸得再厉害些 可能会再次裂开
Takes a bad jolt, she could fracture again.
船长 我不用到甲板上去
I don't have to go on deck, Cap
这里都能听到它的声音
I can hear it from right down here.
那条焊缝真的在响
The weld is really hummin'.
它在响 先生 焊缝... 在响
it's hummin', Sir, the weld is... hummin'.
我请求把船速降到三节
I'd like to take it down to three knots please.
如果不减速
If we don't slow down
船长 我们也许...
Captain, we might not have a...
撑不住的
position to hold.
没问题 船长
No problem, Cap'n.
保持在七节 谢谢 长官
Holdin' at seven knots, thank you, Sir.
- 老爹 - 说吧
- Hey, Pop? - I hear it.
你去甲板上看看
Ya wanna go up on deck have a look at
那条焊缝的止裂铆 好吗
those crack arrestors holdin' that weld together?
最好戴顶帽子去 老爹
You might as well go get a hat, Papo.
他说什么
What did he say?
他说去的时候
He says he'd like you to consider
记得戴顶帽子
taking a hat with ya as well.
睡会觉吧
Get some sleep.
# 大家都叫你坐下 #
For the people all said sit down
# 坐下吧 你让船晃个不停 #
Sit down, you're rockin' the boat
喂 老爹
Hey, Pops!
你了解这种天气吗
What do you know about this weather,
我和小Eldon在这里都被折腾死了
it's killin' me and young Eldon here?
小家伙 你确定是因为天气吗
Tiny, ya sure it's the weather?
也许是被你的歌声搞的
Maybe it's your singin'.
# 大家都叫你坐下 #
For the people all said sit down
# 坐下吧 你让船晃个不停 #
Sit down, you're rockin' the boat
一起唱吧
Come on.
# 人们都叫你坐下 #
The people all said sit down
# 坐下吧 你让船晃个不停 #
Sit down, you're rockin' the boat
闭嘴 闭嘴 闭嘴
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
情况越来越糟了
It's gonna get worse.
Sybert
Sybert!
我没法上甲板去
I didn't make it topside!
这样的海里那条焊缝撑不住的
That weld can't hold in these seas!
必须要减速
Ya gotta slow her down.
我再给船长打电话
I'm callin' the Captain back.
进水了
It's comin' in!
- 你没事吧 老爹 - 没事
- You okay, Pops? - Yeah.
到上面去
Go up!
轮机舱内船体出现了一条裂缝
We've got a hull fracture in the engine room!
所有人 拿上床垫 毯子
All hands! Muster mattresses, blankets,
拿上一切可以拿的
whatever you can get your hands on.
Tchuda
Tchuda.
怎么了
Yeah, boy?
指挥舱没人回话
I can't get anyone on the bridge.
我要你上去告诉船长
I need you to go up and tell the Captain
我们的船体有道十八英尺的裂缝
we got an eighteen foot fracture in our hull.
告诉他这些水泵现在还能撑一下
Tell him these pumps are holdin' for now, but
但如果不及时靠岸 船就要沉了
we don't put her to port, we're gonna wreck.
船长听不懂我的话的 傻子
The Cap'n don't understand me, Balou.
我知道他听不懂你的话
I know he can't understand you,
反正谁的话他都不听
he don't listen to anyone anyway.
天哪 我的上帝
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
- 外面冷吗 - 没错
- Cold out there? - Yeah.
你还在修那个东西吗
Ya still tryin' to fix that darn thing?
是啊
Yeah.
行了 Fitzy 没用的
Ah, c'mon, Fitzy, it's useless.
让能修的来修吧
Let the guy who fixes it to come fix it.
他要在就不用我上了
I would if he would show up.
无线电在说什么 有条船断了吗
What's this on the radio, a ship breakin' up?
是Fort Mercer号
That's the Fort Mercer.
Fort Mercer号
Fort... Fort Mercer?
是艘大船 T2型油轮
She's a big lady, she's a T2 tanker.
几小时前就开始发来无线电
Started radioin' a couple of hours ago,
显然船体出现了大裂缝
apparently she's got a big crack in her hull,
油喷得到处都是
it's spillin' oil all over the place.
位置约在南塔基特以东二十英里
She's about 20 miles east, off of Nantucket.
好像波士顿和南塔基特
It sounds like Boston and
已派出所有的船去营救了
Nantucket are sendin' out their entire fleet.
下面也许就该我们了
We could be next.
他们说暴风的风速
They're saying gale force winds
有每小时五十至六十英里
50 to 60 miles per hour.
是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
浪高五十英尺 完毕
...waves at 50 feet. Over.
真是悲惨啊
It's gonna be a mess.
Bernie Bernie Miriam给你来过电话
Bernie, Bernie, Miriam called for ya.
知道了
Yeah.
祝你好运 兄弟
Good luck, Pal.
- 谁 - Cluff先生
- Yeah. - Mr. Cluff.
是我 长官 Bernie
It's me, Bernie, Sir.
Webber 带上一名队员
Webber, take yourself a crew,
去帮那些渔民
go out there help them fishermen
把码头上的渔船停好
secure their boats to the pier.
好的 长官
Aye, yes, Sir.
长官 我有... 有个请求
Sir, I need to... need t'ask you a question,
请求你准许我... 和一个... 一个姑娘
I need permission 'bout a... 'bout a girl.
准许 准许... 和一个姑娘
Permission, permission... for a girl?
Cluff先生 修好了
Mr. Cluff, it's working.
- 是的 长官 - 现在不谈这个 Webber
- Yes, sir. - Not now, Webber.
但是 长官 这... 不是...
But, no, Sir, it... it's... it's not...
不是一般的姑娘 长官
it's not just some girl, Sir.
现在没空 Webber
Not now, Webber.
现在好了
We're back up.
这一堆船是去营救Mercer号的 对吗
Cluster here is the Mercer Rescue, right?
而这个点 离这里两英里...
This here other pip, two miles from here...
这肯定还是幻象回波
We must still be gettin' phantom echoes.
幻象波是上次同步扫描发射未衰减完全(或遗留到这次同步扫描后)的回波
这肯定还是幻象回波
We must still be gettin' phantom echoes.
这怎么判断
How we suppose to
到底是在哪个位置
tell where anything is out there?
那个技师什么时候能来
When's that technician comin',
Fitzpatrick 该死的Bangs队长又在哪儿
Fitzpatrick, and where the hell's Chief Bangs?
我叫Fitzgerald 长官
It's "Fitzgerald", Sir.
Bangs队长在食堂 长官
Chief Bangs is in the mess hall, Sir.
就因为我不是本地人
You makin' fun of my accent 'cause
你就取笑我的口音是吗
I'm not from around here?
不敢 Cluff先生
No, Mr. Cluff.
Webber 为什么还站在这儿
Why are you still standin' here, Webber?
长官...
Sir, but...
带上Livesey
Take Livesey here with ya,
一起去绑好渔船
go up top them fishin' boats.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
长官 你要我和Webber
Ya want me to go with Webber, Sir,
一起去绑渔船吗
to secure fishing boats?
没听明白吗 Livesey
You didn't hear me, Livesey,
对... 你和Webber一起去
I... yeah, you with Webber.
抱歉 Rich 是他的命令
Sorry, Rich, his orders, ya know.
够了吧 你们有什么想法
That's enough time, whaddya think?
船进了水
We're takin' on water inside,
我们得去坐救生船
we gotta launch some lifeboats.
你真是个混蛋 Brown
Why you gotta be such a jackass, Brown.
我们至少得为
The least we can do
船长 Collagen大副还有其他人
pray for the Captain, Chief Collagen,
祈祷一下 他们都是好人啊
the rest of them men, all good men.
我们不是好人吗 Quirey
Hey, ain't we good men, Quirey?
别误会 祈祷是没错
Don't get me wrong, prayin's great,
但没什么用
but it ain't everything.
现在我们需要的是采取行动
We need to actually do something.
Sybert
借一步说话
A word.
那个鲁莽的Brown
That hothead Brown,
他要去放救生船
he wants to launch the lifeboats.
救生船
The lifeboats?
而Quirey主张什么也别做
Quirey, he wants to do nothin'.
他们
And between them,
让大伙的情绪都不太稳定
the two of them are getting the men worked up.
现在
Now,
我想你是最了解这艘船的人
I figure that you know the boat better than anybody,
你对它最有权威性了 所以...
you're practically married to it, so...
我想他们会听你的
I think they'll listen to ya.
听我的
Listen to me?
老爹 这些人都不喜欢我
Pop, those men don't like me.
除了你和Tchuda 这船上没人喜欢我
Nobody on the ship likes me, but you and Tchuda.
他们也许是不喜欢你
They might not like ya
但他们会明白这事要听你的
but they'll know to listen to ya.
我们不知道船长是否发出了求救信号
We don't know if the Captain got off an SOS.
报务室没了 我们没法求救
The radio room's gone, we can't call nobody.
现在只有... Garcia在这里
Now it's just... just Garcia over here with a
用短波找信号
little shortwave trying to pick up chatter.
就眼下的状况
I mean, as far as we know,
没人知道我们在这里
nobody even knows we're out here.
我觉得趁现在还能走
Now, I'm sayin' we launch some lifeboats now
放下救生船离开这艘船
and get off this ship while you can.
在这样的风暴里
How you gonna get 'em
怎么放救生船呢
down in the water in this storm?
行不通 这些船太小了
It can't be done, those boats are too small,
这等于自杀 Brown
it's suicide, Brown.
这也不能 那也不能
You can't do this, you can' do that,
你要我们怎么办 Quirey
whaddya want us to do, Quirey?
坐以待毙吗
just sit up here, do nothing?
够了 没有领导 没有指令
That's it, no officers, no orders,
只能自寻生路
every man for himself.
不能这样 Brown
That ain't the way, Brown.
这样对谁都没好处
That never did nothin' for nobody.
船是断在八号与九号
Now, the ship's split,
压载舱之间的隔离壁处
at the bulkheads separating tanks eight and nine,
Sybert先生说其他压载舱
Now, Mr. Sybert says the other tanks
没有破裂 所以...
aren't fractured, so...
舱里的空气应该可以让我们继续浮着
the air in the ballast tanks should keep us afloat.
但是Sybert先生也说了...
But, Mr. Sybert also says...
Sybert先生这样说 那样说
Mr. Sybert says this, Mr. Sybert says that,
他是个成年人了 让他自己说
he's a big boy, let him say it himself
他不就在这儿吗
he's right here.
说啊
G'ahead.
船会沉的
We're sinkin'.
但是汽笛还能用
Yeah, but the whistle works.
所以应该让它一直响着
So, we should keep blowin' that,
也许会有人听见
maybe somebody'll hear it.
我也说不清 但船的确是在下沉
I don't know, but we're definitely sinking.
轮机舱的裂缝
The crack in the engine room is takin'
导致大量进水
on too much water,
抽水泵来不及排水
the pumps can't keep up.
如果水位到了引擎进风口
If the water reaches the air intake in the engine,
我们就会失去全部电力
we're gonna lose all the power.
没了电力 抽水泵就转不了
If we lose all the power, we lose the pumps,
抽水泵转不了...
and if we lose the pumps...
船就会很快下沉
she's gonna drop pretty quick.
那我们还能坚持多久
How long have we got before that happens?
也许四到五个小时吧
Four, maybe five hours.
我们得尽量多争取些时间
Well, we need to buy ourselves some time.
让别人可以找到我们
So somebody can find us.
那也得有人看得到啊
If anybody's even lookin'.
即便他们知道我们在这里
Even if they do know we're here
这翻江倒海的天气
the sea is big enough.
船都被劈成两半了
I mean it'd rip this thing in half.
我们怎么出得去
How the hell we gonna get out?
所以我说要放救生船
That's why I'm sayin' we gotta launch some lifeboats.
别再指望好运了
Our luck's runnin' out.
我不相信运气 Brown
I don't believe in luck, Brown.
在这样的海里放救生船
Put those lifeboats in those seas,
撑不过十二秒
they won't last 12 seconds.
你和Quirey就是想坐以待毙
You and Quirey both you just wanna sit around and do nothin'.
你有什么好办法吗 Sybert
You got a better idea, Sybert,
还是干脆躲到下面去算了
or you just go back hide down below?
我们得让船搁浅
We'll run her aground.
什么
Do what?
让它搁浅吗 Sybert
We're gonna run her aground, Sybert?
就算这半条船还能动
Even if you could with half a ship
你这是什么目的
why would you?
它会四分五裂 让我们全掉进海里
Just break apart, dump us all out in the sea.
这是唯一的办法了
It's our only choice,
找一处软浅滩
we're gonna find a soft shoal
在那里搁浅
and we'll lay 'er up,
进水会被减缓
slow the water that's comin' in,
停在那里 再拉响汽笛
stay in the same spot, we'll blow the whistle,
让找我们的人
we'll give whoever's comin' to look
有机会发现我们
for us a chance to find us.
没有了液压系统 怎么驾船
We're gonna steer a ship without hydraulics?
这就是你的计划 怎么行得通呢
That's your plan? How's that gonna work?
做一个手动舵柄
I'll build a manual tiller.
Sybert 为什么我们要听你的
Hey, Sybert, why should we even listen to you?
你只关心这条船
The only thing you ever cared about was this ship,
要我说...
Man, I'll tell you what...
你们俩去海底成双成对吧
You two make a cute couple at the bottom from the ocean.
而我 要上救生船
Me? I'm gonna get onto a lifeboat.
听着
Look.
我们在舵扇里插入一根钢梁
We'll insert a steel beam into the steering quadrant.
另一端挂上滑轮组用来操纵...
We'll put pulleys on the end of it for leverage...
这样就能手动开船了
and then we'll move 'er manually.
对不起 打断下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
无线电好像可以用了
I think I got the radio working.
方位八十三度
Bearing 83 degrees true,
距Pollack Rip灯塔二十七英里
27 miles from Pollack Rip Light,
南塔基特以东约二十英里
about 20 miles east of Nantucket.
南塔基特以东 不是我们Pendleton号啊
East of Nantucket? That ain't the Pendleton.
Fort Mercer号紧急...
Fort Mercer's emergency...
Fort Mercer号 另一艘T2油轮
Fort Mercer, that's another T2.
除了我们还有一艘油轮断成两半啊
Another tanker split in two besides us.
如果全都去救他们了 谁来...
But if everyone's gonna help them, who's gonna...
谁来救我们啊
who's gonna come for us?
你感觉如何 没事吧
How you feelin'? You all right?
- 你... 请示过Cluff了吗 - 还没
- Did you... did you ask Cluff yet? - No.
为什么不请示呢
Why didn't you ask him?
- Webber - 你怎么回事
- Hey, Webber! - What's wrong with you?
- 我还以为... - Webber
- I think I got one more... - Webber!
- 什么事 - 你问了Cluff没有
- What? - You asked him yet, you ask Cluff?
我告诉过你 别说出去
I told you not to tell nobody.
抱歉 我今天不太舒服
I'm sorry, I'm not havin' a very good day.
我知道你身体不好...
I know you're not feelin' well...
Webber 结婚无需批准
You know, Webber, you don't need permission to get married.
- 要的 队长 - 除非你还未到年龄
- No, actually, you do Chief. - Unless you're underage.
谢谢 队长 我只是服从规定而已
Thanks, Chief, just followin' regulations.
我们去换制服吧
Let's go get suited up.
那个不是规定 Webber
It's not regulation, Webber,
只是个形式罢了 礼节性的
it's just a formality, like a courtesy.
还有 我听说是她向你求婚 真的吗
And hey! Did I hear right, that she asked you?
服从命令 Webber
Followin' orders, right, Webber?
对 是她求婚的 队长
Yeah, she asked me, Chief.
Webber 是你有种呢
Are you sure you're got your pants on, Webber,
还是她有种
or is she wearin' 'em?
听上去就像这姑娘割了你的...
Sounds like this girl cut off your pe...
怎么 Webber 怎么了
What, Webber? What? Huh?
你不是要去绑船吗
Don't ya got boats t'tie up?
她... 她是我的未婚妻 长官
She's... she's my fiancée, Sir.
而且主动...
Who asked you...
向你求婚
to be married.
Richie 我们走吧
Come on, Richie, let's go.
请稍等 好的
One moment. Uh-huh, sure.
抱歉 先生 请大点声
I'm sorry, Sir, please speak up.
线路不稳定 女士 我再重接一下
This line is bad, Ma'am, I'll try and re-connect.
请谅解 先生 线路断了
Please, sir, the lines are down.
Bernie 你好吗 工作怎么样
Bernie? How are ya? How's work?
老样子 你好吗
It's been one of those days, ya know, but how are you?
- 你是雷达技师吗 - 不是
- Hey, you're not the radar technician, are ya? - Ah, no.
上面命令我待在这里直到风暴过去
I was ordered to hole up here until the storm passes,
然后搭船回到我的灯塔船
Catch a ride back on my lightship.
你可以在食堂等着
You can go wait in the mess hall if you want to.
现在不太方便
Now is not a good time, ya know.
我得准备去码头
I gotta get ready and go down to the pier,
固定船只 所以...
tie up some boats. So...
真希望你在我身边
I wish you were here with me.
我听说有一艘船
I'm hearin' all sorts of things
在海上断裂了 我...
about a ship breakin'up and I... oh.
怎么了 你没事吧
What, are you okay?
没事 我们的灯灭了
Yeah, we just lost our lights.
那你得去找回来
You better go find 'em, then.
南塔基特已派出那艘三十六英尺的船去救援Mercer号
Nantucket's dispatch their 36-footer to the Mercer.
- 我们也收到了相同的命令 - 你请示Cluff了吗
- We got orders to do the same. - You ask Cluff yet?
那是他在说话 对吧
That's him, right?
还没有 宝贝
No, not yet, Sweet.
- 回头再解释 我得走了 - 好的
- I'll explain later. I just... I gotta go. - Okay.
- 我爱你 - 我也爱你
- I love you. - I love you, too.
再见
Yeah, bye.
神奇的是 她根本不知道我是谁
The best part, she had no idea who I was.
Bangs
Bangs,
你带上队员
pick yourself a crew,
驾驶36-500号离开老港
take the 36-500 outta Old Harbor,
前往南塔基特以东二十英里处的
proceed to the Fort Mercer
Fort Mercer号 听见了吗
20 miles east of here off Nantucket, ya hear?
我觉得这种天气下
Well, I don't believe
我们过不了那片沙洲 Cluff先生
we'd get over the bar in this weather, Mr. Cluff.
最好换成Stage港的36-383号
We're better off takin' the 36-383 outta Stage Harbor.
那会花更多的时间 对吗
Well, it would take longer, right?
不会太多
Not much.
你怎么看 Webber
What do you think, Webber?
你也是水手长
You're a boatswain, too,
知道外面什么情况
you know what it's like out there.
Cluff先生 这种天气下谁也过不了沙洲
Yeah, look, no one's gettin' over the bar
没人做得到
in this weather, Mr. Cluff, nobody,
这无异于自杀
it's a suicide mission.
我们应该开Stage港的36-383号
We should take the 36-383 outta Stage Harbor.
虽然会多花点时间
It would take longer, sure,
但至少能出海
but at least we'll be able to get out.
祝你成功 队长
Godspeed, Chief.
Webber 你带Gouthro和Livesey去渔船码头
Webber, take Gouthro and Livesey down the fishing pier.
遵命 长官
Yes, Sir.
别传染给我 Gus 你就不该出来
Don't get me sick, Gus, you shouldn't even be out here.
你干吗老指责我们 Richie
Why you always raggin' on us, Richie?
别因为你没被Bangs挑上就拿我们撒气
Don't take it out on us 'cause you you couldn't go out with Bangs.
至少他可以出海
At least he'll get out.
去你的 过去都一年了
Screw you, it was a year ago.
去你的
Screw you.
那种天气谁也越不过沙洲
No one coulda got over the bar that day.
Bangs可以的
Bangs coulda.
真的过不了 Richie
No, really, Richie,
今天他也不想去越过沙洲
he's not tryin' to get across the bar today.
他也要开36-383号走海湾边的
No, he said he did 36-383 right out from the nice,
安全路线
protected bayside.
Bernie
Well, Bernie,
Richie还是Bangs还是Nickerson
it doesn't matter what Richie here thinks,
或任何人怎么想并不重要
or Bangs or Nickerson or nobody.
没人可以救出Landry号上的人
Nobody coulda got out to save the men on the Landry.
有时就会劫数难逃 Bernie
Sometimes, ya know, sometimes men die, Bernie.
好了 开始吧
All right, here we go.
抓紧 小心 伙计们
All right, hang on. Easy, now. Easy, fellas.
- 我能行的 - 好 向上抬
- I got it. - Okay, up, up, up.
一 二 现在大家一起
One two, all together now.
三
Three.
- 绑住 小伙子们 - 明白
- Tie it down, boys. - I got it.
好了 现在我们有舵柄了
All right, now we got a tiller
可以把船开到沙洲去了
we're gonna drive her up on a shoal.
Brown和一些人
Uh-uh, Brown and them others
准备放救生船了
they're gettin' ready to launch those lifeboats.
- 他们认为这是唯一的生路 - 哦 老爹
- They think it's their best hope. - Oh, Pop.
我们需要全部人手
We need every guy we got.
他们要上救生船了
Well, they're gonna take the lifeboats.
- 你干什么 Sybert - 放开他
- What are you trying to do, Sybert? - Get off him.
你想要害死我们吗 害死我们吗
You come up here tryin' to kill us? You tryin' to kill us?
放开他
Back off him.
起来
Get up!
你疯了
You're out of your mind!
Brown 他救了你 懂吗
Brown, he just saved your life! Okay?
救生船成碎片了 毁了 你省省吧
The boat's in pieces, it's gone! Enough!
这种海浪这样的小船根本撑不住
That boat is too small for these seas.
而这艘船天黑前就会沉没
And this ship will be sunk by nightfall.
现在要想活命
Now, every fella here wants to live,
唯一的方法
the only way that happens...
就是让船搁浅
is if we run her aground.
安排人瞭望 寻找一处沙洲
We gotta set up a watch and look out for a shoal.
我需要四个人操纵
I need four men working the pulleys
舵柄上的滑轮组
on the emergency tiller.
四个人去操纵船尾舵的抽水机
I need four men manning the pumps, aft of steering.
其他人负责从上到下接力传话
And the rest of you run a bucket line topside down below...
与轮机舱保持沟通
...communicate with the engine room!
还要一个人 负责鸣笛
And somebody... keep blowin' that whistle.
你们都听到了吗 动起来吧 快点
You heard him, boys, now move it, c'mon.
看起来你现在是老大了 Sybert
It sounds like you're the man now, Sybert.
但愿你不会害死我们
I hope you didn't just kill us all.
四十五分钟之前 我在家里
I saw a ship drifting, heard it whistle.
看到有艘船在海上飘着 还听到了鸣笛声 Bernie
A distress signal. 45 minutes ago, Bernie,
是呼救信号
from my house.
风向朝南
With the wind blowing south,
再加上海流作用
and those currents, I, uh...
我猜它现在应该
I guess that'd put her close to here
更靠近这里 要过沙洲了
about now comin' up over the bar.
这不可能是Mercer号 Bernie
It can't be part of the Mercer, Bernie.
它在南塔基特 距这里东南方四十英里
She's off Nantucket 40 miles southeast of here,
应该是往西北方向漂移的 对吗
means she woulda drifted Northwest then, right?
我听得清清楚楚
I know what I heard.
看得清清楚楚
Know what I saw.
那好吧
Well, okay then...
那我们回哨站去
How 'bout we go back to the Station
看看到底什么情况
see if we can get to the bottom of it?
刚刚和波士顿通了电话
Just got off the phone with Boston.
他们的一架飞机绕道离开Merce号时
They diverted a plane from the Mercer,
看到了Pendleton号的船尾
and it sighted the stern of the tanker Pendleton
就在这里以东五英里处
5 miles east of here.
上帝啊 一天之内两艘油轮断裂
My God, two tankers broken in half in one day
该创纪录了吧
that's gotta be some kind of record.
波士顿和南塔基特
Boston and Nantucket have
都派遣了所有船只前往Mercer号
dispatched all their boats to the Mercer.
这种天气他们到不了这里
They can't make it here in this weather.
Webber 你带上一队人
Webber, pick yourself a crew
开那艘36-500号越过沙洲
take that 36-500 out and you go over the bar,
找到Pendleton号的船尾 明白了吗
and you find the stern of the Pendleton, ya hear?
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
你们要喝点咖啡暖和一下吗
You fellas wanna get warmed up, get some coffee?
- Bernie - 什么事
- Bernie. - Yeah?
怎么了
What?
Carl想说的是...
What Carl's tryin' to say...
- 别因为Landry号的事去干 - 肯定就是
- This isn't about the Landry. - Sure it is.
Richie
Richie.
那晚死了八个人
Eight men died that night.
而你 Gus还有Masachi连海都出不去
You and Gus and Masachi couldn't even get out.
你凭什么觉得现在就能做到呢
What makes you think you can do it now?
- 你清楚这时候沙洲是什么样的 对吧 Bernie - 清楚
- You know the bar on this kinda day, right, Bernie? - Yeah.
里面那家伙根本不懂
That man in there don't know what he's doin'
他是在让你去送死
he's sendin' you out to die.
这种天气 你不可能越过查塔姆沙洲
You can't make it over Chatham bar on a day like this.
那半艘船也坚持不了多久
Can't stay afloat for long on half a ship neither.
你也知道 Stello先生 在海岸警卫队
Ya know, Mr. Stello, in the Coast Guard
他们只说要你出去...
they say ya gotta go out...
但没说你非得回来
But they don't say you gotta come back in.
这是规定
That's regulations, ya know.
Bernie 但愿你没开出太远就迷航了
Bernie, better you get lost before you get too far out there.
别担心 Ryder先生
Don't worry about me, Mr. Ryder,
不会迷航的 那片海域我很熟悉
I can't get lost out there, I know those waters pretty good.
怎么会迷航呢
How can I get lost?
不 不 Bernie
No, no, no, Bernie
Dave想说的是 你应该...
what Dave's tryin' to say, ya should just...
绕着码头兜圈子
motor around the harbor,
就说你尽力了 但实在出不去
say you tried to get out, and couldn't.
懂吗
Ya know?
谢谢 Ryder先生 谢谢你
Thank you, Mr. Ryder, thank you..
但是 Stello先生 我会全力以赴出去的
But, Mr. Stello, I'm gonna do my best to... to get out there.
我不知道是否能成功 但一定会尽力的
I don't know if I will, but I'm gonna try.
好吧
Okay.
Richie要参加 还有谁
I guess Richie's in? Who else?
不行吧 Gus 你头都快抬不起来了
I don't know, Gus, you can hardly lift your head.
除了我你还能带谁 Bernie
Who else you gonna take, Bernie?
Fitz是仅剩的引擎师了
Fitz is the only other engineman left.
而他只有三级
And he's only third class,
又缺乏经验
and he don't got the experience.
我愿意去 我... 我...
I... I'll go, yeah, I... I can... I can...
我可以的
I can do the job.
我可以的 你... 你不能去
I mean, I can do it, what, I mean, you... you can't go.
你病得太重了 Gus
You... you're as sick as a dog, Gus.
他说得对 Gus
He's right, Gus.
再来一个
One more.
好吧 总得有人出海
Well, someone has to go out there
去救那些人 对吧
and save those guys, right?
我就是为此入这行的
That's why I signed up.
我想这是我的机会来了
Guess now's my chance.
石马号灯塔船的水手 Ervin Maske
Seaman Ervin Maske, Stone Horse lightship.
抽水泵的速度跟不上了
Pumps aren't keepin' up.
水再涨高三英尺
Three more feet...
引擎就要灭了
then we lose the engines.
你能把那锅炉完全锁紧吗
Can you lock that boiler on full?
你以为用几根绳子外加手工做的舵柄
You're crazy to think you can steer a boat
就能驾驶这艘船 真是疯了 小子
with a few ropes and a handmade tiller, Bud.
你有更好的主意吗 我洗耳恭听
You got a better idea? I'm all ears.
那边 大概一英里处有片沙洲
There! A shoal about a mile distance.
我们能过去的
We can make that!
左舵十五度
Rudder, 15 degrees to port
正面过去的话要半速
half speed if we wanna hit it head-on.
得让船转八十度
Gotta make her turn 80 degrees
罗盘转到三百一十
on the compass to 310.
左舵十五度 半速前进
Rudder, 15 degrees port, half speed,
罗盘转八十度到三百一十
80 degrees to 310 on compass.
左舵十五度 半速前进
15 degrees port, half speed,
罗盘转八十度到三百一十
80 degrees to 310 on compass.
左舵十五度 半速前进
Rudder, 15 degrees port, half speed,
罗盘转八十度到三百一十
80 degrees to 310 on the compass.
左舵十五度 半速前进
Rudder, 15 degrees port half speed...
Rudder, 15 degrees port, half speed...
左舵十五度 半速前进
15 degrees port, half speed...
Rudder, 15 degrees port, at half speed,
罗盘转八十度到三百一十
80 degrees to 310 on compass.
谢谢 Eldon
Thank you, Eldon.
好了 大伙
All right, you guys
现在开始拉 拉 加油
now pull, pull, pull, pull, come on!
我们是要乘那条船去救一艘更大的船吧
Please tell me we're takin' that boat to a bigger boat.
- 你执行过救援任务吗 - 没有
- You ever been on a rescue mission before? - No.
我通常负责刮油漆
Usually I just chip paint
有时候负责做饭
sometimes I cook for the boys.
很好
Great!
好了 你站在这个洞里
All right, you... you take the glory hole.
我叫Maske Ervin Maske
Maske, Ervin Maske.
Ervin 记住了
Ervin, yeah.
Richie 看好时机放下锚绳
Richie, drop the mooring line when you can.
Pendleton号最后的已知位置在这里
The last known position of the Pendleton is here.
所以我觉得 当我们越过沙洲
So I... I figure once we cross the bar,
考虑到水流的因素
I reckon with the currents...
它大概会漂流到这里 距我们六英里处
she'll have drifted about here, that's 6 miles from us.
你觉得Bernie能带我们用这条船越过沙洲吗
So you think Bernie can get us out past bar on this?
我从没见过这样的天气
I never seen anything like it.
他只要能保证我们
Yeah, I mean he's just gotta be sure that
不会翻船就可以了
he doesn't pitchpole us, that's all.
沙洲那儿的海浪
The power in the waves in that bar
能把船掀上天 让你翻上好几个筋斗
they can pick ya up, they can turn ya end for end
翻个不停
over and over again.
不可能活下来的 绝对会翻船
There's no way to survive that, that's a pitchpole.
Fitz 准备好了吗
Hey, Fitz, are we good?
好了 试一下吧
All right, give it a shot!
- 解开绳索 - 解开了
- Free the lines! - Lines free.
Bernie出海了吗 Gus
Did Bernie go out, Gus?
Miriam 你来这里干嘛
Miriam, what are you doing here?
- 他出海了吗 - 是的 Cluff派他去的
- Did he? - Yeah, Cluff sent him.
我要跟他谈谈
I want to talk to him.
- 跟谁谈 - Cluff
- Who? - Cluff.
你们的指挥官 他在哪儿
Your commanding officer, where is he?
我要知道Bernie在哪里
I want to find out where Bernie is,
我很担心他
I'm worried about him.
我们本该结婚的
We're supposed to get married.
Miriam 没有哪个姑娘会像你这样...
Miriam, this isn't what the other girls do...
妻子们都不会
or wives.
她们不会来这里 不会这样的
They don't come in here, and they don't do this.
那又怎样
So?
如果你愿意的话 我觉得...
If you want, I guess... you...
你可以在这里等着听消息
you can wait in here, listen to what's going on.
坐吧
Sit down.
海潮涨起来了 会把我们推离沙洲的
Tide's risin', coulda work us off that shoal.
我们要硬冲了
We need to hit it hard.
是啊 只能这样了
Yeah, there's no other way.
海浪
Wave!
你感觉到了吗 船在漂流
You feel that? She's drifting.
舵柄一定坏了
Must've lost the tiller.
我们得减速
We gotta slow her headway
不然会错过沙洲的
or we're gonna miss the shoal for good.
关闭调速阀 减小推进力
Close the governor valve, cut the propulsion,
锁紧锅炉
we gotta isolate the boiler.
里面的蒸汽都得留着
We gotta conserve everything she's got left.
我跟你说了 这船就是走霉运
I keep tellin' ya... this boat's just bad luck.
这和运气... 没关系
It's got nothing... to do... with luck.
查塔姆站 这里是CG-36-500号船 收到请回复
Station Chatham, this is the CG-36-500, do you copy?
这里是查塔姆站 36-500
This is Station Chatham, 36-500,
请汇报当前位置 完毕
what is your location. Over.
查塔姆站
Station Chatham,
我们... 我们现在正经过莫里斯岛
we are... we are now passing Morris Island,
到了通向查塔姆沙洲的航道 完毕
heading down the channel towards Chatham bar. Over.
越过沙洲是怎么回事
What's it mean going over that bar?
Miriam 别这样
Now, Miriam, don't do this to yourself.
为什么不让我问
Why not?
为什么 Gus
Why not, Gus?
如果我要和他共度一生 我就得知道
If I'm gonna be with him, I wanna know.
- 你就是那个穿着熊大衣的姑娘 是吗 - 对
- You're the girl with the bear-coat, right? - Yeah...
没错 是我
Yeah, that's me.
你要告诉我那里的情况吗
You gonna tell me what's it's like out there?
那片沙洲上的浅滩变幻莫测
Shoals on that bar are never in the same place twice.
海潮带着巨浪
Flood currents carryin' them big ocean swells
遇到浅滩时
that rise up when they hit
会排山倒海般地冲击沙洲
the shallows crash up against that bar.
退潮也会对沙洲形成冲击
The outgoing tide crashes up against that bar.
那个人... 那个人不该让他们
That, uh... That man shouldn't have sent them out
在这样的暴风雪天气去闯滩的
to cross that bar in a storm like this.
他们也许能调头回来
Maybe they can turn back,
也许在那之前就迷航了
maybe they get lost before.
但没法越过沙洲
Can't get out.
你很了解Bernie 是吗
You know Bernie, right?
你知道他不会迷航的
You know he won't get lost out there.
你知道 他一向遵守规则
You know he follows the rules.
是啊 我们都知道
Yeah, we know.
我们等下也会到码头去
We all going down to the pier soon,
看看有什么能做的
see if there's anything we can do down there.
也欢迎你来
Welcome to come.
Miriam
Miriam Miriam 回来
Miriam, Miriam, please come here.
Miriam
Miriam?
抱歉 请问您是Cluff中校吗
Excuse me, are you Commander Cluff?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是Miriam Pentinen Bernie Webber的女朋友
I'm Miriam Pentinen, Bernie Webber's girlfriend,
我想请您命令Bernie回来
I want you to call Bernie back in.
他为了你来请求我
The girl he was askin' me about,
你知道他要请求我什么吗
do you know what he was gonna ask me?
请求您批准我们结婚
For your permission to marry me.
这事你们俩加上上帝同意就行了
Well, that's between you, him and your god.
让我批准只是走个形式
Asking me is just a formality
只要他愿意就可以娶你
he can marry you all he wants.
他不知道吗 不过你不能待在这里 小姐
Don't he know that? But you can't be in here, Miss.
是Bernie
It's Bernie.
查塔姆沙洲就在正前方 完毕
Chatham bar dead ahead. Over.
36-500 这里是查塔姆站
36-500, Station Chatham,
请按指示向Pendleton号船尾前行
Proceed as directed, towards Pendleton stern.
我没听清 查塔姆站
I didn't copy that, Station Chatham,
这里的海况很不好
the conditions hazardous.
你既然让他出去送死 为何还要批准我们结婚呢
Why give us permission if you're sending him out to die?
胡说些什么 Gouthro 把她带出去
What the hell! Gouthro, get her out of here!
长官 从接到呼叫到现在
Sir, winds have gone from 40 to 60
风力已经从四十节增强到六十节
since the call first come in.
此处风力单位可能是英里/小时或海里/小时(节) 美式一海里约为1.15英里 考虑到海上背景可能是以节为单位 40节到60节相当于八级大风到十级暴风
也就是说一小时内可能会增强到飓风
That's gonna be hurricane strength in an hour.
十二级风
也就是说一小时内可能会增强到飓风
That's gonna be hurricane strength in an hour.
Gouthro 他有令在身
Gouthro, he's got his orders.
你带她出去
You get her out of here,
然后自己去睡觉
and you get yourself to bed,
你病了 不该待在这里
you're too sick to be in here.
36-500号 这里是查塔姆站 继续前进越过沙洲
36-500, Station Chatham, proceed over the bar.
重复一遍 继续前进
I repeat, proceed.
成功后 直接向南行驶
Once over, travel directly south.
雷达信号断断续续 但有一个点出现在
The radar's intermittent but it's showing a pip
Monomoy Point以东十到十二英里处
10 to 12 miles east of Monomoy Point,
向南行驶 完毕
moving south. Over.
查塔姆站 这里是500... 收到
Station Chatham, this is the 500... copy that.
大家说的我都听到了
I hear what everyone's saying.
你根本不知道自己在做什么
You don't know what you're doing.
你说什么
Excuse me?
也许... 也许因为你不是本地人
Maybe... maybe it's because you're not from here.
不知道海上的情况
You don't know what it's like out there.
你又怎么会知道
What the hell would you know
海上是什么情况 小姐
what it's like out there, Miss? Hmm?
请命令他们回来吧
Please, just call them back.
你觉得嫁给一名
What do you think it's gonna be like
海岸警卫队员会过一种怎样的生活
being married to a Coast Guard man?
请命令他们回来吧
Please, just call them back.
每次他一出海
You gonna come in here,
你就要失魂落魄地跑来这里吗
scared, every time he out in the water?
请命令他们回来吧
Please call them back.
你不属于这里
You, don't belong here.
请命令他们回来吧
Please call them back.
出去 离开我的哨站
Get out of here! Get out of my station!
回自己的家去 小姐
And go home to where you belong, Miss.
请命令他们回来吧
Please call them back.
滚出哨站
Get out of my station!
我们过头了
Shoal's getting behind us.
现在只有急转弯才有机会
Only chance now is a harder turn,
如果铁链撑得住的话 但...
if the chains hold, but...
也可能会让我们翻船
it could capsize us.
干得不错 孩子
That's good, boy.
站远点 伙计们
You need to stand clear, boys!
要是钩环崩开 铁链断了
If those shackles crack and these chains snap
会把你们劈成两半的
and it'll rip right through ya.
开始
Here we go.
- 船动了 - 没错
- Got her moving! - Yeah!
听见了吗
You hear that?
就是这声音... 沙洲的声音
That's it! That's... that's the bar.
还有几分钟 伙计们
Couple of minutes now, boys.
# 那时我是小儿郎 #
When I was a little boy
# 妈妈如此对我讲 #
So my mother told me
# 我要 起航 起航 #
To me! Way, haul away
# 起航 #
Haul away
# 我们要起航 Joe #
We'll haul away Joe
# 起初我遇到个北方妞 #
Now, first I met a Yankee girl
# 又肥又胖又懒惰 我要#
She was fat and lazy To me!
# 起航 起航 #
Way haul away
# 我们要起航 Joe #
We'll haul away Joe
# 后来遇到个爱尔兰妞 #
And then I met an Irish girl
# 差点没让我抓狂 我要 #
She damn near drove me crazy To me!
# 起航 起航 #
Way haul away
# 我们要起航 Joe #
We'll haul away Joe
# 起航 起航 #
Now way, haul away
# 我们要寻找明媚的风光 #
We're bound for better weather
# 我要 #
To me!
# 起航 起航 #
Way haul away
# 我们要起航 Joe #
We'll haul away Joe
喂 伙计们
Hey, hey, boys,
我们马上要看不清了
we're not gonna be able to see much, all right?
所以只能靠听那些海浪
So we'll have to listen to those waves
打在沙洲上的声音... 来推算它的时间
hittin' that bar... gotta time it.
等它平静下来时 我们就向前冲
So I'm gonna wait for a lull and then we go.
我们相信你 船长
We got faith in you, Skip!
只要你准备好就往前冲 Bernie 好吗
Anytime you're ready, you just go, Bernie, all right?
罗盘不见了
The compass is gone.
Fitzy 引擎熄火了
Fitzy! The engine died!
- 我来搞 - 你不行
- I got it, I got it. - Nah, you don't.
你们只有五秒钟
You got about five seconds, boys!
它是重力式的 所以已经搞不清上下了
It's gravity-fed, it doesn't know... which way is up and down.
我知道
I know!
好了 发动引擎
Come on, fire it up!
Maske 回后面来
Maske! Get back here.
海潮在涨 它会带我们过去的
Tide's rising! It'll get us through.
但我要看一下怎么过
But let me know what's coming.
Fitz 我们闯过沙洲了
Hey Fitz! We made it over the bar.
回到探照灯那边去吧
Back to spotlight!
来了
Coming out!
我们转得太晚了
We turned too late!
得争分夺秒了
We gotta buy that time back!
告诉Sybert 要在两分钟内转三十度
Tell Sybert we need 30 degrees in the next two minutes
不然就会错过浅滩
or we'll miss that shoal!
两分钟内转三十度
30 degrees in the next two minutes!
我们得开倒档
We're puttin' her in reverse.
让海水推着我们走
You're gonna let the ocean push us.
抓紧
Hold on.
你得抓紧了 Eldon
You may wanna brace yourself, Eldon.
三百一十八
318.
三百一十六
316.
一旦搁浅就关掉引擎
Close her down as soon as she hits!
三百一十二
312.
先生们 都抓紧了
Gentlemen! Brace yourselves.
抓紧了
Hold on!
快停
Now!
好了...
Well...
你成功了 居然做到了 Sybert先生
You did it! It bloody well worked, Mr. Sybert!
别让水灌进
We gotta keep the water away
引擎进风口
from the air inlets for the engine.
如果失去了电力 就无法使用抽水泵了
If we lose power, we'll lose our pumps.
而且我担心船舱进水太多
And I'm afraid we're taking on so much water
船的自重会把我们拖离浅滩
the weight will pull us right back off the shoal.
船突然停了是不是反而不习惯了 Eldon
Feels funny to not be moving around, huh, Eldon?
好吧 大家干活吧
All right, let's get to it.
我们要去寄宿站 怎么了
We're heading down to the lodge. Everything okay?
- 住手 - 安静 天哪 让我安静会儿
- Stop it! - Quiet down now, my God, give me a break.
我在回家的路上
I was on my way home,
汽车滑到沟里了
my car spun out into a ditch.
帮帮我
I need some help.
好的 我们就住在附近
Yeah, all right, we live near here.
你可以跟我们回家
We can go back to my house,
我打电话给我哥 让他帮你把车拖出来 上车吧
I'll call my brother, he can pull you out. Jump in.
- 谢谢你 - 你没穿大衣
- Thank you. - You don't got a coat?
把这个挪到一边 我们正要把它送到
You can move that, we're bringing it down to
St. Martin那里去 是为幸存者准备的
St. Martin's in case there're any survivors.
我... 把大衣拉在海岸警卫队哨站里了
I... I left my coat at the Coast Guard station.
你男人在那工作吗
You got a man there?
住手
Stop it.
他现在不在那里 他...
He is not there now right now, it's, um...
- 他叫Bernie Webber - 哦 Bernie是个好人
- It's Bernie Webber. - Yeah, Bernie, he's a good man.
没有罗盘没法找到他们 Bernie
We can't find them without a compass, Bernie!
我们根本不知道他们在哪
We got no idea where they are!
抓稳
Hold on.
- 你没事吧 - 没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
- 你呢 - 我现在好极了 Bernie
- You okay? - I'm havin' a great time now, Bernie!
太好玩了
Lot of fun.
各位抓紧
Brace yourselves!
简直... 简直太过瘾了
Whole lotta... A whole lot of fun here.
- 给 用这个 - 拿到了 老爹
- C'mon, take it. Use it. - Got it, Pop.
抽水泵停了
We lost the pumps.
水泵过载触发了断路器
The pumps are tripping the breakers.
在电路过载时自动切断电路以保护电器设备
水泵过载触发了断路器
The pumps are tripping the breakers.
在电路过载时自动切断电路以保护电器设备
我去检查接口
I'll go check the connections.
在电路过载时自动切断电路以保护电器设备
灯给我
Give me the light.
在电路过载时自动切断电路以保护电器设备
灯给我
Give me the light.
这根本毫无用处 蠢货
It's not worth a damn, Bouloo.
有时候我真希望听不懂你在说什么
Sometimes, I wish I didn't understand you.
Sybert 怎么回事
Sybert, what's going on?
我们开动了所有的水泵
We're using every pump we've got.
只有把断路器卡住 这样水泵就不会触发过载保护了
We jammed the breakers so the pumps wouldn't trip them.
水再涨高两英尺
We've got about two feet till the water
就要灌进引擎进风口了
hits those air inlets to the engines
到那时船就动不了了
and then the ship's dead.
- 天哪 - 你听见了吗
- Jesus Christ. - Do you hear that?
海水在涨潮 会把我们推离浅滩的
That's the tide's rising, gonna work us off this shoal.
但还算幸运 至少争取了一些时间
But luck. This'll at least give us some time.
对吗 Sybert先生
Isn't that right, Mr. Sybert?
没错 的确 伙计
That right, sure it is, boy.
只要发电机继续工作
Yeah, as long as we got generators
维持抽水泵运转
keeping the pumps going.
给那些来营救我们的人
Buy whoever might be coming to find us,
多争取一点时间
we'll buy a little time.
你想做老大 Sybert
You wanted to be the man, Sybert,
现在你是老大了 对吗
now you're the man, right?
但你家中没有老婆 没有孩子
Except you got no wife, you got no kids back home.
孤身一人 舱底就是你的家
You're a single man... always hiding down below,
你有什么可失去的
what do you gotta lose?
行了 Brown
All right, that's enough, Brown.
我也害怕 Brown
I'm scared, too, Brown.
和你一样 我也有自己的生活
I got a life, the same as you.
只是觉得谈论这些毫无用处
Just don't see the point in sitting around talking about it.
查塔姆站 这里是36-500号
Station Chatham, 36-500,
查塔姆站 这里是36-500号 是否收到
Station Chatham, 36-500, do you copy?
查塔姆站 这里是Bangs队长 CG-36-383号
Station Chatham, this is Chief Bangs, CG-36-383,
Pollock灯塔船 这里是CG-36-500号 是否收到
Pollock lightship, CG-36-500, do you copy?
他们为什么听不见 Bernie 我们明明能听见他们
Why can't they hear us, Bernie? We can hear them!
风急浪高 航速为零
Seas are too high, zero headway.
查塔姆站 是否收到
Station Chatham, do you copy?
重复一遍 我们正在返航
Repeat, we're coming home.
查塔姆站 回复36-383号 返航至老港
Station Chatham to 36-383, return to Old Harbor.
Pollock灯塔船 这里是CG-36-500号 是否收到
Pollock lightship, CG-36-500, do you copy?
我们只能靠自己了
We are all alone.
你听见了Bangs在无线电里说的
You heard, Bangs' on the Radio.
看来他没能闯过去 又回去了
It sounds like he couldn't get out, going back in,
风暴越来越大
the storm is getting worse.
我们也该回去 Webber
We should turn back in, Webber.
Bernie 他们认为不可能
Look, Bernie, we already made it out
做到的事我们已经做到了
further than anybody thought was possible!
也许Richie说得对 也许是该回去了
Maybe Richie's right. Maybe we should just go back.
风力达八到九级 重复一遍
Winds at force of 8 to 9, repeat,
风力已达八到九级 有特大暴风雪
winds at force of 8 to 9, heavy snow squalls.
你听见Bangs说什么了
You heard Bangs on the radio!
我们没有罗盘 也没法联络
We have no compass! we have no way to communicate!
- 你真是... - 怎么了 我怎么了 Richie
- You are... - What? What? I'm what, Richie?
我不是把大家都带出这么远了吗
I got us out this far, didn't I?
不是Bangs 不是Cluff 不是别人... 我做到了
Not Bangs or Cluff, not nobody else... I did it!
我们做到了 Richie
We did it, Richie.
你想要返航吗
You wanna turn back around?
不 现在不能 已经走了这么远
No, not now, we came too far.
我们不能放弃他们
We are not giving up on them.
有我在就不行
Not on my watch.
各就各位吧
Just do your job.
Fitz 关掉探照灯 我们要摸黑行驶
Hey, Fitz! Turn off the beam, Fitz, we'll run her dark.
关了灯更容易看见
Better shot at seeing light from the Pendleton
Pendleton号上的灯光
if we're running dark.
当心
Watch it!
回来 Fitz
Get back here! Fitz!
快回来
Get your butts back here!
我的帽子没了
I lost my hat!
你没事吧
You okay?
没事 我只是累了 走吧
Yeah, yeah, I'm just tired. Come on.
你们俩到卧室去玩吧
You kids go on and play in the bedroom.
小姐 我去给我哥打电话 你和他们一起等着
You can wait with them, miss, while I call my brother.
谢谢 叫我Miriam好了
Thanks, please call me Miriam.
我想听收音机
You think your mother would mind
你们的妈妈会介意吗
if I turn on the radio?
波士顿海岸警卫队 这里是Unimak号
Coast Guard Boston, this is the Unimak.
我们现在已到Mercer号船头
We're at the Mercer bow now,
有Yakutat号支援
here in support of the Yakutat.
四名Mercer号船员从甲板跳下海
Four Mercer crew men jumped from the deck,
均已失联
all were lost.
再说一遍 四人失联
Repeat, four men lost.
有些船员出现了低温症
Several crew members have hypothermia.
天亮后我们再开始新一轮营救 完毕
We're gonna for daybreak to attempt another rescue. Over.
听这些没什么好处 Miriam
Does no good listenin' to all that chatter, Miriam...
学会充耳不闻比较好
better learnin'to live not knowin'.
大约晚上七点 我们...
at roughly 1900 hours we...
- 你和Bernie结婚多久了 - 我们...
- How long you been married to Bernie for? - We're...
我们还没结婚
We're not married yet.
我不知道是不是...
I didn't know if I...
我说过 Bernie是个好人
Like I said, Bernie, he's a good man.
一年前 他和其他人试图出海
Him and some of them others try gettin' out a year ago,
营救我丈夫Arnie和Landry号上的船员
save my husband Arnie and the crew of the Landry.
他们当时在南塔基特湾附近捕马林鱼
They were out fishin' marlin near Nantucket Sound
船进了水
when the boat started takin' on water,
也是像这样的一个夜晚
A night just like this.
来吧 我们要走了
Come on, we gotta get goin'.
我哥在来的路上了
Brother's on his way to come meet us.
我得去寄宿站了 你们俩过来
I gotta get down to the lodge, come on, you two.
# 大家都叫你坐下 #
For the people all said sit down
# 坐下吧 你让船晃个不停 #
Sit down, you're rockin' the boat
# 大家都叫你坐下 #
For the people all said sit down
# 坐下吧 你让船晃个不停 #
Sit down, you're rockin ' the boat
# 魔鬼会拉着你的花格外套尖衣领 #
And the devil may pull you under
# 把你拖入水底 #
By the sharp lapels of your checkered coat
# 坐下吧 坐下吧 #
Sit down, sit down, sit dow
你知道她是谁吗
Do you know who she is?
Carly 不是Bernie的错 不是任何人的错
Ain't Bernie's fault, Carly, nobody's fault,
不然她也能怪你
Be like her blaming you.
为什么怪我
For what?
是你告诉他们那里还有一艘船
You're the one that told them there's another ship out there,
所以他们才出海的 对吧
they're out there because of you, right?
Fitz 打开探照灯
Fitz, turn on the searchlight.
难以置信 我们竟然找到了 快看
I can't believe we found her, look at that!
我们来迟了 船上没人了
We're too late, she's a ghost ship.
- 你看到了吗 长官 - 看到了
- Are you seeing this, Sir? - Yeah.
- 你看到那个人了吗 - 是的 我看到了
- You see that guy? - Yeah, yeah, I see him.
真不敢相信
Not sure I believe it.
他这是去哪儿了
Where is the hell's he goin'?
见到你们太好了
Good to see you, boys.
小心
Careful.
我们这船怎么装得下他们所有人
How we gonna fit them all on this boat?
这船只能载十二个人 包括我们在内
We're only built to hold 12, including us.
那只是规定 对吧
That's just regulation though, right?
实际可以装多少人
How many could he fit?
二十个 最多二十二
Twenty, twenty-two tops.
等等
Wait.
他们要下来了
They comin' down here.
放下支柱 在左舷
Drop the stanchion Port side.
快过来
Come on!
来 我拉住你
Come on, I gotcha.
我们接着你
We got ya.
Maske 这边
Maske, get over here!
快 拉住他
Come on! Grab him!
知道要去哪里吗 小姐
You know where you goin' now, Miss?
应该知道
I think so.
谢谢你的帮助 Nickerson先生
Thanks for your help, Mr. Nickerson.
不谢
Yeah.
你知道
You know...
Bernie不是因为我才出海的
Bernie ain't out there, 'cause of me.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know.
这是他的职责 不是吗
It's Bernie's job to go out, right?
我怎么会怪你呢
How can I blame you for it?
慢慢来 慢慢来 你可以的
Nice and slow! Nice and slow! You'll be all right.
Pete 你是下一个
Pete, you're next.
- 慢慢来 别着急 - 来吧
- Take it nice and slow! Easy! Easy! - Come on.
你也走吧 大家都得走
You gotta go! We're leavin' nobody behind.
- Eldon 顺着梯子下去 - 让他下去
- Eldon, get on that ladder. - Come on, we gotta get him down.
船倾斜了 得赶紧离开
She's slippin', we gotta get off this ship.
快点
Hurry!
Eldon 还好吧
Eldon, how you doin'?
我很害怕
I'm scared.
嗯
Well...
只剩你一个在这里的话 就更害怕了
Gonna be a lot scarier up here without us.
你得听我说
You gotta listen to me!
- Eldon - 我们都会下去的 别挤了
- Eldon? - We're all gonna get off, stop pushin'!
你跟着我就好
You just follow right behind me...
如果我都能做到 人人都可以
if I can do it, anyone can.
来吧
Come on.
抓紧
Hold tight!
小个 小个 坚持住
Tiny! Tiny! Hold on!
Eldon Eldon
Eldon, Eldon.
Eldon 看着我 看着我
Eldon, look at me! Look at me!
我说跳你就跳 准备好了吗
When I say, "Jump", let go! Ready?
跳
Jump!
你还好吗
You okay?
抓紧
Hold tight.
船太重了 已经很难掌舵了
They're ridin' so heavy, you can hardly steer.
他们说甲板上还有七八个人
Sir, they're saying there's still 7 or 8 up there on board.
要不 我们先把这些人带回去 再回来
Maybe... we take these guys back in... come back out.
不能丢下他们 那艘船撑不了多久了
Can't leave 'em out here alone, that boat won't last.
我们要同生共死
We all live or we all die.
对吗
Right?
你... 你真是好样的
You... you did good.
你应该最后一个离开 Sybert先生
You should be the last one off, Mr. Sybert.
最后一个了
Last man!
Fitz 关掉探照灯 好吗
Hey Fitz! Turn off that searchlight, yeah?
我们用无线电联系了McCullough号
We were in radio contact with the McCullough,
他们说四个人殒命了 其余都获救了
They said they lost 4 men, but saved the rest.
Pollock Rip号的船长说他们...
The captain of the Pollock Rip sent word that they...
Cluff先生 是36-500号 是Bernie
Mr. Cluff, it is 36-500, it's Bernie.
联系上他们了
It's right there on the radio.
查塔姆站 收到请回答
Station Chatham? Station Chatham, copy?
CG-36-500号 这是查塔姆站
CG-36-500, this Station Chatham.
Webber 是你吗
Webber, is that you?
是的 是我 Bernie
Yes, Sir, it's me. It's Bernie.
我们从Pendleton号沉船上
We got 32... 32 survivors aboard
营救了... 三十二名幸存者
from... from the sinkin' Pendleton, Sir.
查塔姆站 听到了吗
Station Chatham, do you copy?
36-500号 这里是查塔姆站
36-500, Station Chatham,
你是说你的船上有三十二名幸存者吗
did you say you have 32 survivors on board?
他们救了三十二个人
They rescued 'em, they rescued 32 of them.
是的长官 三十二个
Yes sir, 32.
我们... 我们的罗盘丢了
We... we... we lost our compass,
所以不知道现在身在何处
so we don't know where we are,
但我们会努力回去的
but we're gonna try to make it back home.
没有罗盘可回不来
Can't get back without a compass.
尤其在这种天气
Not in this weather.
他们回不来的
They're not gonna make it back.
你们的罗盘丢了 Webber
You lost your compass, Webber?
不行 36-500号 这里是Pollock灯塔船
Negative, 36-500, this is the Pollock lightship,
不要去岸边
do not proceed to shore.
我们在Pendleton号
We're 5 miles northeast of
最后已知位置的东北方五英里处
the Pendleton's last known location.
到我们这里来 完毕
Proceed to our position. Over.
CG-36-500号 这里是查塔姆站
CG-36-500, Station Chatham,
前往Pollock灯塔船 转移所有幸存者 完毕
proceed to Pollock lightship and unload all survivors. Over.
他们又知道什么
What do they know, right?
对吧 Richie
Right, Richie?
CG-36-500号 听到请回答
CG-36-500, do you copy?
如果他们知道自己的位置
If they know where they are...
就会说出我的位置
someone tell me where I am
因为我不知道我们身在何处
'cause I don't know where the hell we are.
Webber 听到请回答
Webber, do you copy?
我不想再往外面走了... 不
I'm not headin' out to sea... no.
这是查塔姆站 听到请回答
This is Station Chatham, do you copy?
刚把你们从一艘船上救下来
We just got you all off a... off a boat,
我们不想
so there's no way we're...
再把你们搁在海上了
we're gonna get you all up there.
CG-36-500号 这是查塔姆站
CG-36-500, this is Station Chatham.
Webber 我命令你
Webber, your orders are to proceed
向东北方向行驶五英里
five miles northeast
将幸存者转移到Pollock号
and unload all survivors onto the Pollock.
他好像切断了无线电 Cluff先生
Sounds like there's a cut off his radio, Mr. Cluff...
他要按自己的方式来
he's going it on his own.
Bernie Webber
Bernie Webber.
你料得到吗
What do you know?
他们要怎么样才回得来
How are they gonna find their way home?
他肯定关了无线电
He must have shut off the radio.
- 可怜的人 - 不敢相信怎么会这样
- Poor, poor boys. - I can't believe this is happenin'.
车上还有东西没拿下来
Some more stuff in the car.
停电了
The power's out.
整个城都停电了
The whole town, the power's out.
- 比去年还糟糕 - 他们回不来了
- It's worse than last year. - They'll never make it.
咱们去码头吧
Let's get to the pier.
没有罗盘你们是怎么找到我们的
How did you find us without a compass?
我们... 只是顺着海流走
We... we just jogged along with the seasonal currents.
可能比较幸运吧
I think we just got lucky.
- 是啊 - 是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah...
幸运
Lucky.
那你知道怎么回去吗
So, you know how you get home?
说实话 我也不确定
To be honest with ya, I'm not sure.
我... 没有听从上级的命令
Just... disobeyed all my ranking officers.
他们不了解情况 我比他们清楚一些 对吧
They don't know, so I guess I... I'd better, right?
来的时候风是从左面吹来的
Had the wind on my left goin' out,
我想 如果一直保持风在右面
Figure if I... . Keep it her on my right,
方向应该不会错
we oughta be headin' the right direction.
我们只要跟随岸上的灯光
We just follow the lights onshore,
跟随岸上的一切灯光
follow all the lights onshore.
我们都靠你了 船长
Well, we are in your hands, Cap'n.
大家听着
Listen up.
我要向岸边前进
I'll put the sea behind us.
让海水推着我们走 直到找到陆地
Just let it push us along, till we land up somewhere.
风暴... 风暴在逐渐平息 所以
The storm's... the storm's easing' up, boys, so...
我们只需找寻岸上的灯光
we just look for the lights on the shore to guide us in.
即使要走到遥远的Nobska灯塔
Even if we have to go so far as Nobska Point.
也要往前走 我们一定会找到陆地的
So be it! We just gonna find land!
今天可是无比漫长的一天 对吧
Been one heck of a long day, right fellas?
的确如此
Yeah, it sure has!
但是你们要对我有信心
But don't you give up hope on me now.
这船不错 会让我们度过难关的
It's a good boat, she'll get us through.
我们会把你们带回家 我们都会回家
We'll get you home, okay? We're all goin' home.
我们相信你 船长
We're with you, Skipper.
大家像她一样把车灯打开
Keep the lights on, like she's doin'!
快点 开灯
Quick! Turn your lights on!
大家都把灯打开
Turn on the lights, everyone.
把灯打开 他们就能看到我们了
More light, so that they can see us.
看来我们已越过沙洲了
I think we made it over the bar.
是海潮把我们带过来的
That high tide carried us over!
看到了吗
You see that?
Fitz 打开探照灯
Fitz, turn on the searchlight.
- 看 看到了吗 - 是我们的人吗
- Look, you see that? - Is that our boys!
是他们吗
Is it them?
干得漂亮 Bernie
Well done, Bernie!
- 你做到了 Webber - 干得好 Webber
- You did it, Webber! - Well done, Webber!
36-500号正在靠近查塔姆码头
36-500 is now docking at the Chatham pier.
看来有三十二名幸存者 长官 再说一遍
There appear to be 32 survivors, Sir. Repeat,
共三十二人获救
we have 32 survivors.
很好
That's right.
扔过来 孩子
Throw it, son.
好小子 Bernie
Atta boy! Bernie.
拉他们一把
Give 'em a hand.
- 见到你们真好 - 快上来
- Good to see you. - Get on up here.
慢慢来
Nice and easy.
还以为再也见不到你们了
We never thought we'd see you again.
这位要冻僵了 给我件大衣
This man's freezing, get me a coat.
快进去 里面暖和
Go on in, it's warm inside.
去寄宿室吧
Let's get you up to the lodge.
下一位 我抓住你了
Next up. Come on, now. I got you.
干得好 船长
Good job, Cap'n.
好样的 Bernie
Way to go, Bernie.
Webber
Webber?
Bernie
Bernie.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
我们还是四月十六日结婚吗
Are we still good for April 16th?
- 是的 - 是的
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我替你请示过Cluff了
I asked Cluff for ya.
- 他说这只是一种形式而已 - 形式
- He said it's just a formality. - Formality.
现在我知道了
Now I know, right?
伯尼·韦伯 理查德·李甫西 安迪·菲茨杰拉德 和 欧文·马斯基
于1952年2月18日夜晚所完成的壮举
至今仍被誉为海岸警卫队历史上最伟大的小船救援行动
伯尼和米丽娅姆在选定的日期完婚
他们的婚姻持续了58年 直至伯尼以81岁的高龄
于2009年去世
伯尼和米丽娅姆在选定的日期完婚
四位海岸警卫队队员也因这一壮举
获得了金质救生奖章
怒海救援